<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Application Customization on Sparta Documentation</title>
    <link>/reference/application/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Application Customization on Sparta Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/reference/application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Application Commands</title>
      <link>/reference/application/custom_commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reference/application/custom_commands/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In addition to custom flags, an application may register completely new commands. For example, to support alternative topologies or integrated automated acceptance tests as part of a CI/CD pipeline.
To register a custom command, define a new cobra.Command and add it to the sparta.CommandLineOptions.Root command value. Ensure you use the xxxxE Cobra functions so that errors can be properly propagated.
httpServerCommand := &amp;amp;cobra.Command{ Use: &amp;#34;httpServer&amp;#34;, Short: &amp;#34;Sample HelloWorld HTTP server&amp;#34;, Long: `Sample HelloWorld HTTP server that binds to port: ` + HTTPServerPort, RunE: func(cmd *cobra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Flags</title>
      <link>/reference/application/custom_flags/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reference/application/custom_flags/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Some commands (eg: provision) may require additional options. For instance, your application&amp;rsquo;s provision logic may require VPC subnets or EC2 SSH Key Names.
The default Sparta command line option flags may be extended and validated by building on the exposed Cobra command objects.
Adding Flags To add a flag, use one of the pflag functions to register your custom flag with one of the standard CommandLineOption values.
For example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Environments</title>
      <link>/reference/application/environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reference/application/environments/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s common for a single Sparta application to target multiple environments. For example:
 Development Staging Production  Each environment is largely similar, but the application may need slightly different configuration in each context.
To support this, Sparta uses Go&amp;rsquo;s conditional compliation support to ensure that configuration information is validated at build time. Conditional compilation is supported via the --tags/-t command line argument.
This example will work through the SpartaConfig sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow Hooks</title>
      <link>/reference/application/workflow_hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 19:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reference/application/workflow_hooks/</guid>
      <description>Introduction While Sparta tries to provide workflows common across service lifecycles, it may be the case that an application requires additional functionality or runtime resources.
To support this, Sparta allows you to customize the build pipeline via WorkflowHooks structure. These hooks are called at specific points in the provision lifecycle and support augmenting the standard pipeline:
mermaid.initialize({startOnLoad:true}); graph TD classDef stdOp fill:#FFF,stroke:#A00,stroke-width:2px; classDef userHook fill:#B5B2A1,stroke:#A00,stroke-width:2px,stroke-dasharray: 5, 5; iam[Verify Static IAM Roles] class iam stdOp; preBuild[WorkflowHook - PreBuild] class preBuild userHook; compile[Cross Compile for AWS AMI] postBuild[WorkflowHook - PostBuild] class postBuild userHook; package[ZIP archive] class package stdOp; userArchive[WorkflowHook - Archive] class userArchive userHook; upload[Upload Archive to S3] packageAssets[Conditionally ZIP S3 Site Assets] uploadAssets[Upload S3 Assets] class upload,packageAssets,uploadAssets stdOp; preMarshall[WorkflowHook - PreMarshall] class preMarshall userHook; generate[Marshal to CloudFormation] class generate stdOp; decorate[Call Lambda Decorators - Dynamic AWS Resources] class decorate stdOp; serviceDecorator[Service Decorator] class serviceDecorator userHook; postMarshall[WorkflowHook - PostMarshall] class postMarshall stdOp; uploadTemplate[Upload Template to S3] updateStack[Create/Update Stack] inplaceUpdates[In-place λ code updates] wait[Wait for Complete/Failure Result] class uploadTemplate,updateStack,inplaceUpdates,wait stdOp; iam--preBuild preBuild--|go|compile compile--postBuild postBuild--package package--packageAssets package--userArchive userArchive--upload packageAssets--uploadAssets uploadAssets--generate upload--generate generate--preMarshall preMarshall--decorate decorate--serviceDecorator serviceDecorator--postMarshall postMarshall--uploadTemplate uploadTemplate--|standard|updateStack uploadTemplate--|inplace|inplaceUpdates updateStack--wait  This diagram is rendered with Mermaid.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>